[
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "import from the string module provides a convenient and efficient way to access all lowercase letters of the English alphabet for string manipulation or processing tasks",
    "answer": "from string import ascii_lowercase"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Write a function get_frequencies() that takes a single parameter called filename",
    "answer": "def get_frequencies(filename):"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Initialize a dictionary to store frequencies of each lowercase letters with all frequencies starting at zero using dictionary comprehension in Python",
    "answer": "frequencies = {letter: 0 for letter in ascii_lowercase}"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Open a file and read its contents and Convert its content to lowercase to count all instances",
    "answer": "with open(filename, 'r') as file:\n text = file.read().lower()"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Count the frequencies of each letter, insert it into the frequencies dictionary and return the dictionary ",
    "answer": "for letter in text:\n    if letter in ascii_lowercase:\n        frequencies[letter] += 1\n    return frequencies"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Write a function get_status_codes() to determine the frequencies of the web status codes in a file. The function should: take a single parameter representing a filename & return a dictionary containing the status codes and their corresponding frequencies in the file. For now just intilaize the function, we will step through the rest in the next questions",
    "answer": "def get_status_codes(filename):"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Open the file and read its contents",
    "answer": "with open(filename, 'r') as file:"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Split line into components and get the status code Assuming status code is the last component",
    "answer": "for line in file:\n components = line.split()\n status_code = components[-1]"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "If status_code not in dictionary  Insert status_code into dictionary as key with value 1 Otherwise Add 1 to the value for the this status_code (as key)",
    "answer": " if status_code not in status_code_freq:\n  status_code_freq[status_code] = 1\n else:\n  status_code_freq[status_code] += 1"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "finally return status_code_freq",
    "answer": "return status_code_freq"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Write a function get_frequencies()",
    "answer": "def get_frequencies(filename):"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Initialize a dictionary to store frequencies of each lowercase letters",
    "answer": "frequencies = {letter: 0 for letter in ascii_lowercase}"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Open a file and read its contents and Convert its content to lowercase to count all instances",
    "answer": "with open(filename, 'r') as file:\n text = file.read().lower()"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Count the frequencies of each letter, insert it into the frequencies dictionary and return the dictionary ",
    "answer": "for letter in text:\n    if letter in ascii_lowercase:\n        frequencies[letter] += 1\n    return frequencies"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Write a function get_status_codes() to determine the frequencies of the web status codes in a file. The function should: take a single parameter representing a filename & return a dictionary containing the status codes and their corresponding frequencies in the file. For now just intilaize the function, we will step through the rest in the next questions",
    "answer": "def get_status_codes(filename):"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Open the file and read its contents",
    "answer": "with open(filename, 'r') as file:"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "Split line into components and get the status code Assuming status code is the last component",
    "answer": "for line in file:\n components = line.split()\n status_code = components[-1]"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "If status_code not in dictionary  Insert status_code into dictionary as key with value 1 Otherwise Add 1 to the value for the this status_code (as key)",
    "answer": " if status_code not in status_code_freq:\n  status_code_freq[status_code] = 1\n else:\n  status_code_freq[status_code] += 1"
  },
  {
    "category": "other",
    "question": "finally return status_code_freq",
    "answer": "return status_code_freq"
  }
]